## **SOKOBA Aboubakar Christian**

### Senior Fullstack Developer

With 6 years of web development experience in agile environments, I've acquired strong technical and soft skills. Staying on top of technical good practices ensures the relevance of my skills. I'm ready to contribute to future projects, bringing my knowledge, rigor and drive to help build reliable applications and have a good impact on my team.

# +33 7 81 65 74 90 sokobachristian@yahoo.fr

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SFR**, Paris — Senior Frontend Developer

June 2024 - PRESENT

Development on the SFR Web-TV application:

- UI enhancements, feature implementation, and bug fixes
- Development of the purchase/rental journey for video-on-demand (VOD) and the video player
- Implementation of audience analytics tools for players (Live, VOD, trailers, etc.)
- Refactoring and framework updates

Technical Environment: Angular 18, Nx, RxJS, Jenkins, Atlassian Suite

#### Carrefour, Paris— Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

2021 - 2024

Development from scratch of an invoicing application:

- Front and back-end development of features and customer journeys. +10M € of invoicing and thousands of invoices per day in production.
- Coordination with partner API teams, complexity evaluation and participation in architecture design.
- Backend development on several microservices with Java 11 and Spring boot, code review, improvement of developer experience.
- Improvement of application performance by solving network and architecture bottlenecks
- Participation in writing user stories specifications and grooming
- Planning and supervision of Pre-production and Production releases with the DevOps

Technical environment: Angular 14+, Java 11 + Reactor, Spring Boot, Kubernetes, Postgres, GitLab, Cypress, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence

#### **Orange**, Paris — Fullstack Software Engineer

2019 - 2021

Fullstack development on the 'Espace Client Digital' in a SAFe context

- Development of 15+ several high business value customer pages for a 15+ Millions unique visits per month website. UI/UX integration in a design system context
- Development in a modular micro frontend architecture feature teams organization, angular updates and code migrations
- Backend development of REST microservices in NodeJS
- Refactoring, improvement of existing code, implementation of integration, unit and end-to-end tests
- Facilitating the professional growth and skill enhancement of interns through structured guidance and support.

Technical environment: Angular 11, NodeJS 14, Javascript, Typescript, Git, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Jenkins, VS Code, Jest, Jasmine, Mocha, Protractor, Jira, Confluence, Postman

#### **SKILLS**

Angular Java NodeJS HTML, CSS, TYPESCRIPT

Critical thinker Fast learner Clear and excellent communicator

#### **Education**

2019 Diploma of Telecommunication and Network Engineer at Institut Sup Galilée, Paris

#### Certifications

AWS Cloud Practitioner 2023

UX-PM1 2022

#### **LANGUAGES**

English: Proficient, TOEIC 720

French: Native